lore.com 2012-10-30

# Privacy – Lore

## Lore, Inc. Privacy Policy

_Last Updated Date: April 23, 2012._

___________________________________________________________________________________

Lore, Inc. (“ **Lore** ” or “ **we** ”) provides a platform which enables course or group leaders (“ **Instructors** ”) and course or group members (“ **Students** ”) to manage their educational courses and other groups (“ **courses** ”) through our website, accessible at _[www.lore.com](http://www.lore.com/)_ (the “ **Site** ”; and the services provided through such Site, the “ **Service** ”).  Using the Site, Instructors create courses where Students (and other users where the course, or certain course-pages within the course, are made “public” by the Instructor and so generally readable by the public) can access materials and information related to the course, and where Instructors and Students can post messages and updates about course-related topics.  We want to make communication between Instructors and Students, and between Students, easier so that learning can be more interactive and fun.

Lore provides this privacy policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information we receive from users of the Site.  This Privacy Policy applies only to information that you provide to us through this Site.

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time.  If we modify this Privacy Policy we will post the modification on the Site or provide you with notice of the modification.  We will also update the “Last Updated Date” at the top of this Privacy Policy.  You are advised to consult this policy regularly for any changes.  Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms of Use (“ **Terms** ”), available at the top of this [page](http://lore.com/privacy-security/).  “ **Member** ”, as used in this Privacy Policy, refers to a person that completes Lore’s account registration process, whether as an Instructor or as a Student, as described under the “Account Registration” section of the Terms.

As used in this Privacy Policy, the terms “using” and “processing” information include using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within the United States or internationally.

**Public & Private Courses**

Instructors, when creating a course or at any time thereafter, can choose whether the different pages within the course (e.g., the syllabus, the calendar, the list of members and the course-stream) will be “private” or “public.”  If every page within the course is “private”, the name of the course may still be visible to the public, but the course-pages will only be available to Members who join the particular course.  If all or certain pages within the course are public, these course-pages (e.g., the syllabus, the calendar, the list of members and the course-stream) will be generally readable by the public, although individual grades and submissions will always be visible only to the Instructor and the particular Student. **IF YOU ARE AN INSTRUCTOR, PLEASE CAREFULLY CONSIDER DESIGNATING COURSE-PAGES AS   “PRIVATE” OR “PUBLIC.”**  **IF YOU ARE A STUDENT, PLEASE BE AWARE THAT AN INSTRUCTOR CAN CHANGE A “PRIVATE” COURSE-PAGE TO A “PUBLIC” COURSE-PAGE AT ANY TIME; PLEASE KEEP THIS IN MIND WHEN SETTING YOUR PRIVACY SETTINGS IN YOUR ACCOUNT.   **(See the “Information Sharing and Disclosure” section below for further information.)

**Information Collection and Use  
**

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Site, Service, features and content, to administer your membership and to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate the Site.

_Personally Identifiable Information_ _:_    
Personally identifiable information is information about you that can be used to contact or identify you (“ **Personal Information** ”).

When you register with us through the Site as a Member, we will ask you for Personal Information.  Personal Information includes, but is not limited to, your name and email address.  Other Personal Information we collect depends on whether you’re an Instructor or a Student.  For example, if you’re a Student, depending on the course you join, we may ask you to provide the name of the school you attend, your field of study and your graduation year, or the name of your employer.  Similarly, if you’re an Instructor, we may ask you to provide the name of your employer and your field of study or practice.  If you are a Student, we may also collect Personal Information about you from your Instructor.  For example, your Instructor may provide us with your email address in order to invite you to join a course (See “Emailing and Messaging Via Lore” below).  In addition, if you register with us through the Site as a Member, you specifically consent to your Instructor disclosing to Lore your grade for any course of which you are a Member, so that Lore can enable you to receive your grade through the Site, and any notes the Instructor chooses to record in the Instructor’s account, so that Lore can enable the Instructor to more easily track your progress in and contributions to the course; you also acknowledge that the Instructor can change the course from a “private” course to a “public” course and vice versa at any time.  In addition, the Student’s name and email address will always be visible to the Instructor of each course in which the Student is a member irrespective of the Student’s individual privacy settings.

We also collect the other information that you provide as part of registration and the administration and personalization of your profile webpage ( _e.g._ , without limitation, individual preferences) (“ **Non-Identifying Information** ”).

We use your Personal Information (in some cases, in conjunction with your Non-Identifying Information) mainly to provide the Service and administer your inquiries.

We may also use your Personal Information ( _e.g._ , your email address) to contact you with Lore newsletters, and Lore and our partners’ marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you.  If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or contact us at _[privacy@lore.com](mailto:privacy@lore.com)_.

Certain Non-Identifying Information would be considered a part of your Personal Information if it were combined with other identifiers (for example, combining your zip code with your street address) in a way that enables you to be identified.  _But_ the same pieces of information are considered Non-Identifying Information when they are taken alone or combined only with other non-identifying information (for example, your viewing preferences).  We may combine your Personal Information with Non-Identifying Information and aggregate it with information collected from other users and by our third party service providers (such as Google Analytics and KissMetrics) to attempt to provide you with a better experience, to improve the quality and value of the Service and to analyze and understand how the Site and Service are used.   We may also use the combined information without aggregating it to serve you specifically, for instance to deliver a product to you according to your preferences or restrictions.

_Log Data_ _:   _  
When you visit the Site, whether as a Member or a non-registered user just browsing, our servers, or our third party service providers on our behalf, automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website ( ** _“_ Log Data _”_** ).  This Log Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (or “IP”) address, browser type or the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Site, pages of our Site that you visit, the time spent on those pages, information you search for on our Site, access times and dates, and other statistics.  We use this information to monitor and analyze use of the Site and the Service and for the Site’s technical administration, to increase our Site’s functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor it to our users’ needs.  For example, some of this information is collected so that when you visit the Site again, it will recognize you and may serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your interests.  We also use this information to verify that users of the Site meet the criteria required to process their requests.  We do not treat Log Data as Personal Information or use it in association with other Personal Information, though we may aggregate, analyze and evaluate such information for the same purposes as stated above regarding other Non-Identifying Information.

**Cookies  
**

Like many websites, we, or our third party service providers on our behalf, use “cookies” to collect information.  A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes.  We use cookies for two purposes.  First, we utilize persistent cookies to save your registration ID and login password for future logins to the Site.  Second, we utilize session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Site, to better understand how you interact with the Site and to monitor aggregate usage by users and web traffic routing on the Site.  Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Site and Service and then close your browser.  You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit.  If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site or all functionality of the Service.

**Emailing and Messaging Via Lore  
**

As part of the Service, Instructors can invite people to join their courses via email through the Site.  Where Instructors have selected the option of adding one or more email addresses to the online form, the message they create in the corresponding template will be sent from Lore to those email addresses on their behalf.  These email addresses will be used only for the purpose of sending the email invitation to the addressee.  In addition, as part of the Service, each Instructor and Student can communicate with other Members, by email or by using our chat tool, and Members can communicate with each other and with other users by posting to the course-page. Members may also receive notifications of course activity by email.

**Phishing**

Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to Lore.  Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is a top priority.  We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, your account ID, login password, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication.  For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission’s website. ****

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

_Lore Users_ :  
As a Member (whether you are an Instructor or a Student), we will display your Personal Information in your profile page and elsewhere on the Site according to the preferences you set in your account (through the account settings section of the Site).  Any information you choose to provide should reflect how much you want other Lore users to know about you.  Please keep the following in mind when setting your preferences: (i) some courses available through Lore are “private” courses, in that the course-pages are only available to Members who have joined the particular course, while other courses available through Lore are “public” courses, in that the course-pages are generally readable by the public; and (ii) the Instructor for a particular course can change the privacy settings that apply to the course at any time and so a course that may have been “private” when you joined may in the future become a “public” course.  We recommend that Members think carefully about what information about themselves they disclose in their profile pages and what preferences they set in terms of who they want that information to be shared with.  You can review and revise your profile information and preferences at any time.

_Aggregate Information and Non-Identifying Information_ :  
We may share aggregated information that does not include Personal Information and we may otherwise disclose Non-Identifying Information and Log Data with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling and other purposes. Any aggregated information shared in these contexts will not contain your Personal Information.

_Service Providers_ :  
We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Site-related service ( _e.g._ , without limitation, maintenance service, database management, web analytics and improvement of the Site’s features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Site and Service are used.  These third parties may have access to your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

_Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement_ :  
Lore cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law.  We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of Lore or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, any illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

_Business Transfers_ :  
If the ownership of our business changes, we may transfer your information to the new owner so they can continue to operate the Service.

**Changing or Deleting Your Information  
**

All Members may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in their registration profile through the Site.  If you completely delete all such information, then your account may become deactivated. If you would like us to delete your record in our system, please contact us at _privacy@lore.com_ with a request that we delete your Personal Information from our database.  We will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor your request.  We may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. **  
**

**Security  
**

Lore is very concerned with safeguarding your information.  The security of your Personal Information is important to us.  No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, however, is 100% secure.  Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.  We also require you to enter a password to access your account information. Please do not disclose your account password to unauthorized people.

We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored “personal data” (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or conspicuous posting on this Site in the most expedient time possible, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.

**International Transfer**

Your information may be transferred to – and maintained on – computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be the same as those in your jurisdiction.  If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, Lore transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes it there.  Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

**Links to Other Sites  
**

Our Site contains links to other websites.  If there are advertisements on the Site and you choose to visit an advertiser by “clicking on” a banner ad or other type of advertisement, or click on another third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s website.  The fact that we link to a website or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices.  We do not exercise control over third party websites.  These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you.  Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them.  We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit. **  
**

**Our Policy Toward Children**

The Site and Service are not intended for use by persons who are 13 or younger.  Any access to or use of the Site or Serviceby anyone 13 or younger is expressly prohibited except in the limited circumstances described below.

We will not make the Site and Service available to persons who are 13 or younger, and you are prohibited from inviting or permitting persons who are 13 or younger to join a course created by you, unless a written agreement is in place between Lore and the school or school district you work for permitting Lore to collect personal information from students for the use and benefit of the school or school district in compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).

If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at _[privacy@lore.com](mailto:privacy@lore.com)_.  If we become aware that a person under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will take measures to delete such information from our files.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us at _[privacy@lore.com](mailto:privacy@lore.com)_.
